SIVAKAMI SADASIVAN

sivakami.sadasivan@gmail.com+971 54 489 3205Dubai Silicon Oasis, Dubai, UAE



Visa Status: Husband Visa

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Proven experience developing consumer-focused web sites using HTML, CSS, JQuery, Angular, Wordpress and JavaScript. Use Adobe Creative Suite programs, e.g., Photoshop, Illustrator and figma to mockup UI elements. Experience building products for desktop, phone and mobile app users, meeting highest standards for web design, user experience, best practices, usability and speed. Use visual aids such as wireframes, storyboards and UI flow charts, to plan and present user interface designs. Responding to challenges by designing and developing solutions and building web applications aligned to customer's services.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ASV Building and Construction Material Trading LLC, Dubai, UAE

Web and Graphics Designer, Present

- Create company website using HTML, CSS and JavaScript and they are consistent across all browsers and platforms.
- Create effective design documentation including mockups and wireframes.
- Implement creative design for Company logo, marketing packages, posts for social media using Photoshop and Illustrator.
- After implementing, update UI changes as per the needs and requirements.
- Managing Cpanel server.

VINIIDEAS TECHNOLOGIES, UI Developer, Part time

- Develop functional and appealing web and mobile-based applications based on usability.
- Create web pages using HTML, CSS and JavaScript for angular projects that are consistent across all browsers and platforms.
- Creating quality mockups and prototypes.

FittGROUP, Dubai, UAE - Web and Graphics Designer, 08 Feb 2020 - 30 May 2021

- Designing, coding and modifying websites, from layout to function and according to client's specifications
- Designing responsive web pages using HTML, CSS, JavaScript technologies and wordpress.
- Developed creative design for marketing packages, including print materials, brochures, banners and signs in Illustrator and Photoshop.
- Created new designs and periodic updates to company websites to meet modern web standards.
- Creating websites using Wordpress CMS.
- Cpanel Management

SPERIDIAN TECHNOLOGIES, UI/UX Designer, 07 Sept 2017 – 12 Dec 2019

- Work according to Product Development's Sprint schedule and providing timely high fidelity prototypes
- Provide UI designs through consideration of business requirements & technical limitations using Photoshop
- Converted the design into responsive, interactive features, using HTML/CSS, bootstrap and JavaScript for Angular project.
- Provide QA and feedback to developers
- Work closely with back-end developers to implement and deliver final products
- Scrum Methodology
- Provide responsive design for desktop and mobile platforms.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Designing Software : Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Figma

Project management : Adobe Dream Weaver, Notepad ++, Visual Studio Code, Gitlab,

FTP, Filezila, Cpanel Management

Operating System : XP, Windows 7, Windows 8, Windows 10
Core Skills : HTML, HTML 5, CSS, JavaScript, Photoshop,
MS Office (Word, Powerpoint, Excel) etc.

Techniques : Web standards, Design Patterns, Wordpress

EDUCATION

B.TECH DEGREE, RAJADHANI INSTITUTE OF ENGINEERING AND TECHNOLOGY, INDIA, 2012-2016

Bachelor of Technology in computer science Engineering.

PROJECTS

WORDPRESS WEBSITES

Jambo Times

Jambo Times is an online community portal for African Expats working and living in the Middle East. Jambo Times delivers essential information and news covering everything that matters to Africans.

- URL: https://www.jambotimes.com/
- Developed website using HTML, CSS3 and Wordpress.

Jambo Jobs

International Recruitment and Jobs Portal for Africans. Jambo Jobs is the site for full time, part time and hourly jobs for Africans

- URL: https://www.jambojobs.com/
- Developed website using HTML, CSS3 and Wordpress.

NatureBorne

- URL: https://natureborne.com/
- Developed website using HTML, CSS3 and Wordpress.